# JEFF D. MEAD

Software Development

Phone: 908-229-2034 LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/jeff-mead-58b6b8136/</u>

Email: Jeffdmead171@gmail.com
Twitter: twitter.com/JDM\_Management
GitHub: https://github.com/JMead171

Full-Stack Developer pursuing a position in software development with a professional organization that will challenge and use my talents and experience for both mutual growth and success. Experienced in JavaScript programming; developing, testing and debugging code; designing interfaces; and administering systems and networks. Quickly learn and master new technologies; successful working in both team and self-directed settings. Have an MBA in business operations and several years of business operational experience.

# Languages & Proficiency Hard Skills Soft Skills

JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Node.js, React Coding, Debugging, Program Analyst Business Acumen, Leadership Express.js, GitHub, MERN, APIs Software Development, Researching Personnel Management MongoDB, MySQL,VS Code, COBOL

## **Projects**

### What's Your Beef

#### GitHub: https://github.com/JMead171/whats-your-beef | Deployed: https://salty-island-84425.herokuapp.com

- Summary: Ecommerce site for food products. Allows users to view and place orders using a shopping cart
- Core responsibilities: JWT authentication, offline indexDB, service worker, web manifest, media queries, Heroku and readme
- Technology used: MERN, JavaScript, NoSQL, PWA, React SPA, GraphQL API, JWT authentication, offline indexDB, service worker, web manifest and Heroku.

#### Virtual Office Coordinator

## GitHub: https://github.com/JMead171/vo-coordinator | Deployed: https://vo-coordinator.herokuapp.com

- Summary: Virtual office coordinator that allows an office manager to communicate with their employees.
- Core responsibilities: JavaScript logic for API routes, the add/update task section, MongoDB Atlas, Heroku and debugging.
- Technology used: Node.js, JavaScript, ORM, API Routes, Express.js, MySQL2, Sequelize, doteny package.

#### **Tech Blog**

# GitHub: https://github.com/JMead171/tech-blog | Deployed: https://arcane-oasis-62399.herokuapp.com

- Summary: This project is a CMS-style blog site, that can publish articles, blog posts, and thoughts and opinions.
- Core responsibilities: JavaScript logic, API routes, MySQL, handlebars, media queries, readme
- Technology used: Node is, JavaScript, ORM, API Routes, handlebars, Express is, MySOL2, Sequelize, doteny package

#### Experience

# Full Stack Developer / Freelance

2020

Writing, refactoring, optimizing and debugging code across multiple applications to ensure the functionality of the code is working efficiently and correctly. Researching and Analyzing new concepts and programming languages for enhancing future projects. Major areas of training include: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Node.js. React, MERN, GitHub, GIT, SQL and NoSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, APIs, Express.js and MVC.

#### **Business Management/Operations Consultant**

JDM Management Inc., NJ

2017 to 2020

Owner and CEO of JDM Management, expert in combining financial, business and technology planning for organizational success. Focused to optimize long-term gains in performance, revenues and profitability for small businesses.

### **Director of Operations**

The Kokes Organization Real Estate Firm, NJ

2003 to 2017

Managed the daily business operations for a mid-size Real Estate Firm consisting of over 100 employees and over \$10 in annual revenue. Business activities included Sales, Budgeting, Forecasting, Financial Reporting, CRM Software, IT Support, Strategic Planning and Company Financial & Sales Presentations.

#### Computer Programmer/Analyst

Scudder, Stevens & Clark, New York City, NY

1996 to 2002

Developed and Managed Programming Projects. Develop and coded computer software for financial systems using COBOL & CICS. In addition, created CICS interface and maintained computer software for the reconciliation of financial transactions between brokerage houses and bank institutions. Also, managed overnight batch processing for software and data updates to the financial system.

### **Education**

### BootCamp Certificate: University of Central Florida, FL

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS

## Masters of Business Administration: Monmouth University, Long Branch, NJ

Major Business Management and Administration.

# Bachelor of Science: Georgian Court University, Lakewood, NJ

Major Business Management and Administration.

## Computer Science Certificate: Brick Computer Science Institute, Brick, NJ

A 13-month program focused on mainframe programming in COBOL and CICS.